Thompson, S. mss., LMC 2421
Lilly Library
- Genealogy
  - Thompson family (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Virginia Thompsons (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - Correspondence, 1923-1972 (Box 9, Folder 36)
      - Notes (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Faust, Noble, Lacy, and Ross families (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Misc. Kentucky families (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Misc. Washington, Co., and Nelson Co., Kentucky (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Clippings (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Notebook (Box 9, Folder 42)
- Printed Materials, 1911-1969
  - Thompson, Stith. (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Pater's Theory of Style. California Occident 61, no. 4: 40-48., (December 1911) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - The Value of the Ideal of Social Reconstruction Set Forth in Tolstoy's What Shall We Do Then? The Truxton Beale Prize Essays on Tolstoy's 'What Shall We Do Then?' Berkeley: University of California Press,: 123-176., 1912 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      (Inscribed: "To the folks at home. With love, Stith.")
    - The Prehistoric Development of Satire. Publications of the Folk-lore Society of Texas No. 1: 78-95., (1916) (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Edited by Thompson
    - The Notebook System of Theme Correcting. The English Bulletin No. 4: 17-22., (December 1917) (Box 10, Folder 3)
      (Part of University of Texas Bulletin no. 1767, Dec. 1, 1917)
    - Sunday School Stories Among Savages. The Texas Review 3, no. 2: 109-116., (January 1918) (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - European Tales among the North American Indians: A Study in the Migration of Folk-Tales. Colorado College Publication No. 34, (April-May 1919) (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - The Indian Legend of Hiawatha. Reprinted from The Publications of the Modern Language Association of America 37, no. 1, (1922) (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - The Best Books about the Ballad. The English Bulletin No. 10 (University of Texas Bulletin no. 2245,: 5-7)., December 1, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Review of Volksverhalen Uit Oost-Indië (Sprookjes en Fabels) by Jan de Vries. Journal of American Folklore: 79-81., (1929) (Box 10, Folder 4)
      (Personal copy)
    - Program for the Premiere of Heloise and Abelard performed in Alumni Hall (Indiana University)., May 22, 1934; (January-March 1935) (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Poem by Stith Thompson on verso of cover.
    - Review of The Heart of the Skyloo by Ottis B. Sperlin. Indiana University Alumni Quarterly 22, no. 2: 197., (Spring 1935) (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Folktale Congress in Sweden. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore 49, no. 191-192, (January-June 1936) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Personal Notes on a Folktale Congress. Indiana University Alumni Quarterly 23, no. 1: 1-17., (Winter 1936) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Review of Three Lectures on Chinese Folklore by R. D. Jameson., (March 1936) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Review of The Sun God Moccasin Tales by Albert B. Reagan Indiana University Alumni Quarterly 23, no. 3: 349-350., (Summer 1936) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Congress for the Study of the Folk-Tale at Lund. Reprinted from American Anthropologist 38, no. 4: 687., (October-December 1936) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Review of Volkssagenforschung: Vorträge un Aufsätze by Friedrich Ranke. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore 50, no. 195, (January-March 1937) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Review of Zuni Mythology by Ruth Benedict. Reprinted from American Anthropologist 39, no. 2: 337-338., (April-June 1937) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - American Folklore after Fifty Years. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore 51, no. 199: 1-9., (January-March 1938) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Folklore News. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore 51, no. 199: 95-99., (January-March 1938) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Folklore News. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore 52, no. 203, pg. 117. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Folktale Collecting in Ireland. Southern Folklore Quarterly 2, no. 2: 53-58., (June 1938) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - The International Organization of Folklore. Reprinted from Southern Folklore Quarterly 2, no. 4: 195-198., (1938) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Review of Manuel de Folklore Francais Contemporain by Arnold Van Gennep. Reprinted from Journal of American Folklore, (1939) (Box 10, Folder 6)
      (2 copies)
    - Folklore and Literature. Reprinted from Publications of the Modern Language Association of America 55, no. 3: 866-874., (September 1940) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Review of Ballads and Songs Collected by the Missouri Folklore Society by H. M. Belden (Ed.). Reprinted from the Journal of English and Germanic Philology 40, no. 4, (October 1941) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Folklore of the Americas: An Opportunity and a Challenge. Proceedings of the Eighth American Scientific Congress, (1941) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Review of Svenska Sagor och Sägner by Kungl. Gaestav Adolfs Akademien. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore 52, no. 204, (1941) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Some Recent Publications from Argentina. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore 54: 86., (1941) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Review of European Balladry by William J. Entwistle. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore: 207-208., (1941) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - The Miller's Tale. Reprinted from Sources and Analogues of Chaucer's 'Canterbury Tales' Edited by W. F. Bryan & Germaine Dempster. University of Chicago Press,: 106-123., 1941 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Galley sheets of Shipley's Encyclopedia Folktale, Folklore, Mythology, Historical-Geographical Method, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Review of The Dance of Death in Folksong by Henri Stegemeier. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore, (1943) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Women Students in War Time. The Eleusis of Chi Omega 47, no. 2: 273-275., (May 1945) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Folklore and Minnesota History. Reprinted from Minnesota History: 97-105., (June 1945) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - The Scholar in a New World. The Rainbow of Delta Tau Delta 69, no. 2, (February 1946) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - and Tabor, Edward O.Paul Bunyan in 1910. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore: 134., (April-June 1946) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Review of Folktale, Fiction, and Saga in the Homeric Epics by Rhys Carpenter. Reprinted from Western Folklore :313-314., (1948) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Folklore in South America. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore: 256-260., (July-September 1948) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - John Avery Lomax (1867-1948). Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore: 305-306., (July-September 1948) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Folklore--Classification and then what? Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore: 423., (October-December 1949) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - The Future of Folklore Research in the United States. Reprinted from Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society 93, no. 3: 244-247., (1949) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Review of A Harvest of World Folktales Edited by Milton Rugoff. Reprinted from Folklore and Folklorists: 181., (April 1950) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Folklore Conferences at Indiana University. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore: 459., (October-December 1950) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Story-writers and Story-tellers. Reprinted from Philologica: The Malone Anniversary Studies: 228-234., (1950) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Folklore at Mid-century. Reprinted from Midwest Folklore: 5-12., (1950) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Review of Ritual Magic by E. M. Butler. Clip sheet from Modern Language Quarterly 12, no. 3: 361., (September 1951) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Review of Thespis: Ritual, Myth and Drama in the Ancient Near East by Theodore H. Gaster. Reprinted from the American Journal of Archaelogy 55, no. 4 :412., (October 1951) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Review of A Bibliography of North American Folklore and Folksong by Charles Haywood. Reprinted from American Anthropologist 53, no. 4: 553-554., (October-December 1951) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Review of Heavy Hangs the Golden Grain by Seumas MacManus. Reprinted from Western Folklore, (October 1951) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Review of English Riddles from Oral Tradition by Archer Taylor. Reprinted from the Journal of English and Germanic Philology 51, no. 2: 242-244., (April 1952) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Folktales and Legends Reprinted from The Frank C. Brown Collection of North Carolina Folklore Vol. 1, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Folklore and Folk Festivals. Reprinted from Midwest Folklore 4, no. 1 (n.d.): 6-12. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Review of Poison-Damsels and other Essays in Folklore and Anthropology by N. M. Penzer. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore 66, no. 261: 275., (July-September 1953) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Advances in Folklore Studies. Reprinted from Kroeber, (ed.) Anthropology Today. University of Chicago Press,: 587-596., 1953 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - The Beauchamp Family. Reprinted from The Filson Club History Quarterly 28, no. 2: 1-39., (April 1954) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Review of The Oldest Stories in the World by Theodor H. Gaster. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore 67, no. 264: 225-226., (April-June 1954) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Review of American Folksongs of Protest by John Greenway. A. H. R. (?), (1954) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Review of Folktales from Korea by Zong In-Sob, Modern Greek Folktales by R. M. Dawkins, and African Folktales and Sculpture by Paul Radin and James Johnson Sweeney. Reprinted from Southern Folklore Quarterly 18, no. 3: 194-197., (September 1954) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - The Indian Legends since 'Hiawatha.' Michigan History 39, no. 4: 462-463., (December 1955) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Sigurd B. Hustvedt, 1882-1954. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore :200., (1955) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Myths and Folktales. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore: 482-488., (1955) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Recollections of an Itinerant Folklorist. Address to the Texas Folklore Society, May 20, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Review of The Micmac Indians of Eastern Canada by Wilson D. Wallis and Ruth Sawtell Wallis. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore 69, no. 274: 398., (October-December 1956) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Can Religion Surmount Folklore? The Christian Unitarian Register 136, no. 1: 10., (January-February 1957) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - The Study of Primitive Storytelling: Its Present Status and Future Directions. Reprinted from Folk-Liv, (1957-1958) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Comparative Problems in Oral Literature. Reprinted from the Yearbook of Comparative and General Literature No. 7, Chapel Hill, North Carolina, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Prepared Comments for the Journal of American Folklore 72, no. 285: 232., (July-September 1959) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Review of Legend Builders of the West by Arthur M. Young. Galley sheet from the Classical Journal 55, no. 4: 192., (January 1960) (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The Historian and the Genealogist. The Filson Club History Quarterly 34, no. 2: 160-165., (April 1960) (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Review of The Anatomy of Puck: An Examination of Fairy Beliefs among Shakespeare's Contemporaries and Successors by Katharine M. Briggs. Reprinted from Shakespeare Quarterly 11, no. 3: 367., (Summer 1960) (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - 1930: A National Survey of Freshman English. College English 22, no. 2: 78-80., (November 1960) (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The Significance of Near Eastern Folklore. Reprinted from Biblical and Jewish Folklore, (1960) (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Fifty Years of Folktale Indexing. Reprinted from Humaniora: Essays in Literature, Folklore, Bibliography: 49-57., (1960) (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Review of Cuentos Folkloricos de la Argentina. Journal of American Folklore 74, no. 292: 173-174., (April-June 1961) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Folklore Trends in Scandinavia. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore: 313-320., (1961) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Review of German Folktales Collected and edited by the Grimm Brothers. Reprinted from the Journal of English and Germanic Philology: 116., (January 1962) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence Journal of American Folklore 76, no. 300: 182., (April-June 1963) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Review of Volksmärchen und Volkssage: Zwei Grunelformen Erzählender Dichtung by Von Max Lüthi. Reprinted from the Journal of English and Germanic Philology 62, no. 4: 889-890., (October 1963) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Review of Dancas do Norte e do Sul by Zärde Maciel de Castro. Reprinted from Western Folklore 23, no. 1: 59., (January 1964) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - American Folk Tradition. The Review (Indiana University Bulletin) 6, no. 2: 1-15., (February 1964) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Review of Die Volkserzählung: Märchen, Sage, Legende, Schwash. by Von Leopold Schmidt. Reprinted from the Journal of English and Germanic Philology 63, no. 3:595-596., (July 1964) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - The Challenge of Folklore. Reprinted from Publications of the Modern Language Association of America 79, no. 4, part 1: 357-365., (September 1964) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Folktale Typology and the Pacific Area. Reprint from Folklore Studies in Honor of Arthur Palmer Hudson. Chapel Hill,: 11-18., 1965 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Obituary of J. Frank Dobie, 1888-1964. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore, (1965) (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - A Humanist's Creed. Unitarian Universalist Church Sermon Series, (February 1966) (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - American Folk Tradition. In Folklore ed. by Charles D. Blaney. Indiana Council of Teachers of English, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - An Office Boy Remembers 1902. The Indiana University Bookman No. 8: 7-9., (March 1967) (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Review of Das Märchen. Sein ort in der Geistigen Entwicklung by Von Hedwig von Beit. Reprinted from the Journal of English and Germanic Philology 66, no. 1: 107-108., (January 1967) (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - On MacEdward Leach, 1892-1967. Reprinted from the Journal of American Folklore 81, no. 320:119., (April-June 1968) (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Personal (photo) copy of Reminiscences of an Octogenerian Folklorist by Hari S. Upadhyaya. Reprinted from Asian Folklore Studies 27, no. 2, (1968) (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Review of Formen der 'Volkspoesie' by Von Hermann Bausinger. Reprinted from the Journal of English and Germanic Philology 68, no. 2: 373., (March 1969) (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Analogues and Borrowings in North and South American Indian Tales. Languages and Cultures of Western North America: Essays in Honor of Sven S. Liljeblad Idaho: Idaho State University Press,: 277-288., 1970 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Unfinished Business: The Folktale. Reprinted from Medieval Literature and Folklore: 213-221., (1970) (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Foreword. Indiana Folklore 4, no. 1: 1-2., (1971) (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Foreign Publications, (1934-1969)
      - Handwörterbuch des deutschen Märchens, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Fassung (Variante). Handwörterbuch des deutschen Märchens (n.d.) (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Gegenspieler. Handwörterbuch des deutschen Märchens (n.d.) (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Purpose and Importance of an Index of Types and Motifs. Folk-Liv No. 1: 103-108., (1938) (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Por qué Estudiamos el Folklore? Conferencia 11, no. 6-9: 84-93., (June-December 1947) (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Desarrollos Recientes de los Estudios Folklóricos en los Estados Unidos. Revista Venezolana de Folklore 1, no. 2: 3-12., (July-December 1947) (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - El Cuento Folklorico. Separata de la Revista de la Universidad de Buenos Aires 1, no. 2: 235-272., (1947) (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - La Mitologia. Folklore Americas 11, no. 1: 1-15., (June 1951) (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - The Star Husband Tale. Etrait de Laos II: 7-10., (1952) (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - La Leyenda. Folklore Americas 12, no. 1: 3-11., (June 1952) (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - The Star Husband Tale. Studia Septentrionalia 4: 93-163., (1953) (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Advances in Folklore Studies. Il Tesaur 5, no. 4-6, (July-December 1953) (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Narrative Motif-analysis as a Folklore Method. FF Communications 64, no. 161: 4-9., (1955) (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Review of Folklore de las Americas by Felix Coluccio. Erasmus 9, no. 1-2: 43., (1956) (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Overdruk uit Volk skunde ?, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Report on the Revision of the Types of the Folktale. Internationaler Kongreß der Volkserzählungsforscher in Kiel und Kopenhagen.: 428-431., (1959) (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - El Metodo de Clasificar y Archivar los Cuentos Folkloricos. Congresso Internacional de Folklore, (1960) (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Colloquium on the Folktale. Actas do Congresso Internacional de Etnografia, (1963) (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Review of Thompson's work: The Types of the Folktale by J. Van Haver. Leuvense Bijdragen, (1965) (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - As Metas do Folclore. Separata da Revista Brasileira de Folclore 5, no. 11: 33-48., (January-April 1965) (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - De Wekroep van de Volkskunde. Volkskunde No. 1: 1-19., (1966) (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Icelandic Parallels among the Northeastern Algonquians: A Reconsideration. Offprint of Nordica et Anglica: 133-139., (1967) (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Planes Preliminares para un Servicio de Folklore en Venezuela. Archivos Venezolanos de Folklore No. 8, (1967) (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Hypothetical Forms in Folktale Study. Volksüberlieferung: 369-372., (1968) (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Story-telling to Story-writing. Proceedings of the 5th Congress of the International Comparative Literature Association: 433-442., (1969) (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Ting, Nai-Tung.Introducing the Second Revised Edition of Antti Aarne and Stith Thompson's 'The Types of the Folktale.' Reprinted from the Tsing Hua Journal of Chinese Studies 7, no. 2, (August 1969) (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Posters:
      - Congreso Internacional de Ethnografia, Portugal, July 10-16, 1963 (Ovflat 31)
      - Unidentified poster in Hebrew (Ovflat 31)
      - Stith Thompson lecture at SUNY-Buffalo, Feb. 27, 1969 (Ovflat 31)
      - Stith Thompson lecture in Colombia, SA, Feb. 13, 1961 (Ovflat 31)
    - Scrapbook containing clippings, ca. 1904 (Box 15)
- Additions
  - Biographical - funeral service program for Stith; photo of 1890 school house and family tombstone, biographies, photograph and information about bust. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Louise to daughters (mostly), 1933-1935; (photocopies) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Stith to Louiseand, 1917; 1918; 1931; (photocopies) (Box 11, Folder 4-6)
    - Louise to Stith, 1916-1919; (photocopies) (Box 11, Folder 7-9)
    - Family, 1917-1920; (photocopies) (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Misc. letters to Stith, 1951; 1971-1975 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Sympathy cards and letters upon Louise's death, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Sympathy cards and letters upon Stith's death, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Photographs (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Six photographs. Includes several of Stith as young man (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Writings. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - The Stith Thompsons on a Folklore Expedition in Europe, 1937; diary by Louise Thompson (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - South American Journey, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - A Half Year in Scandinavia by Louise Thompson., June 1951-Feb. 1952; (2 copies) (Box 11, Folder 17-18)
    - Iceland, Denmark, Holland: by Stith and Louise Thompson, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Folklorist's Progress by Stith Thompson, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Doing Europe on a Guggenheim, 1956-1957; diary by Louise Thompson (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Further Adventures in Europe of the Stith Thompsons, Summer 1959 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - South America Revisited by the Stith Thompsons, 1960-1961; diary by Louise Thompson (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Holland, Belgium, France, Italy by Louise Thompson, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Greece by Louise Thompson, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Second Wind, A Sequel After Ten Years to Folklorist's Progress, April 1966 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Six weeks in Europe by Louise Thompson, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous writings. (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Includes: A Humanist's creed, by Stith Thompson
  - Guestbooks and scrapbooks (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - 1918, Wedding guestbook (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - 1935-1976, scrapbook of clippings, programs, etc. for Stith (disassembled) (Box 12, Folder 8-11)
    - 1946, scrapbook of Folklore Institute (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - 1968, 50th Wedding anniversary, includes scrapbook (disassembled), guestbook, cards and letters, clippings, photographs, book of poems by Sue Letsinger (Box 12, Folder 13-18)
    - 1974, funeral service guestbook for Louise (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - 1975, scrapbook commemorating Stith's 90th birthday (disassembled) (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Clippings (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Postcards (blank), mostly of other countries (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Printed (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Travel brochures, menus, etc. (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Miscellany (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Scrapbook commemorating Stith's 80th birthday, 1965 (Box 14)
    - Clippings from foreign newspapers about folklore, 1943-1959 (Box 15)
    - Scrapbook of certificates and citations, 1935-1970 (Box 16)
- Scrapbook thanking Stith Thompson, from delegates of the Midcentury Folklore Conference, Bloomington, IN, July 22-Aug. 5, 1950 (Box 13)
- Stith Thompson Memorial Resolution (Box 13)
- Correspondence, 1950; 1975; 1984 (Box 13)
- Correspondence on Centenary, 1984-1985 (Box 13)
- Meeting programs, 1950; 1954 (Box 13)
- Interview transcript (Box 13)
- Travel writings (Box 13)
- Encyclopedia Britannica, Folk Literature correspondence and excerpts, 1969 (Box 13)
- Newspaper clippings (Box 13)
- Printed materials (Box 13)
- Photographs (Box 13)
- Notes and maps (Box 13)
- Notes on tale types (Box 13)
- Monographs on tale types (Box 13)